Muhammad Uzair

Cell# 0342-8388817 | uzairsuleman786@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammaduzairsuleman/

Profile Summary

Graduated in Bachelor of Computer Sciences, with an experience in web development and software engineering. Excellent deadline driven, analytical and effective communication skills with the talent for analyzing problems, developing and simplifying procedure and finding innovative solutions for job efficiency. Flexible, dependable and work very well with others as well as independently.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science	
Institute	Bahria University Karachi Campus.
Duration	2016-2021
CGPA	3.10

Experience

<u>Jr. Analyst Programmer – Dubai Islamic Bank</u> <u>Pakistan (MAR 2021 – Present)</u>

- 1. Window Form Applications, ASP.NET Web Applications including Web Forms, WebAPIs and MVC
- 2. SQL Server, Oracle 12c
- 3. Web Service, Rest APIs

WordPress Development - Internship - The Next Rex (Pvt) Limited (DEC 2020 - MAR 2021)

- 1. Design, dynamic and ecommerce site
- 2. Improve skills on front end.
- 3. Get firm hands on WordPress and website designing.

Software Skills

- 1. Visual Studio, C# .NET
- 2. Object Oriented Programming
- 3. Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio, PL/SQL
- 4. Flutter
- 5. Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- 6. WordPress
- 7. Python
- 8. PHP

Projects

- 1- ATM Management System (C++, OOP)
- 2- Bank Management System (C++, Data Structure)
- 3- Travelling Agency Website (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- 4- Travelling Management System (.NET)
- 5- Pensioner Bio Verification System (.NET)
- 6- 1-Link Per-Payment (.NET CORE, WebAPIs)
- 7- Roshan Digital Account (.NET CORE, WebAPIs)
- 8- Digital Onboarding Solution (.NET CORE, WebAPIs)
- 9- E-Commerce Website (WordPress)
- 10-Identify Sarcastic Tweets via Text and Emoji (FYP, Python)

Interpersonal Skills

Time Management

Creativity

Self - Motivation

Teamwork

Certificates

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures:

freeCodeCamp.org | 29/11/2021.

Digital Marketing:

Google Digital Garage | 13/07/2020.

Languages

English/Urdu

Professional Proficiency

References

References available on request